A cavalry seems to be approaching.
好像有马队逼近
It should just be passing by.
应该只是路过
Even if they want to kill me, they won't do it on an official road.
要杀我也不至于在官道动手
What's wrong?
干吗
Do you know the woman?
那女的你认识
Xuanyuan Qingfeng.
轩辕青锋
The Xuanyuan Family of Hill Guniu of Mount Hui.
徽山牯牛大岗上的轩辕世家
Yes.
正是
The Xuanyuan Family of Jiangdong.
江东轩辕
Do you know it, too?
你也知道
Of course I do.
当然知道了
The family
轩辕世家
has a foundation of hundreds of years.
有着数百年的基业
It controls the water transport
天下江流水运
of the world.
皆在轩辕门下
There is an old monster in the family,
轩辕家还有个老怪物
Xuanyuan Dapan.
轩辕大磐
He's reached Celestial Realm.
已是天象境
Diamond Realm, Void Realm, Celestial Realm.
金刚 指玄 天象
Is he of the same realm with Wang Xianzhi?
那不是跟王仙芝一个境界了
Xuanyuan Qingfeng?
轩辕青锋
Isn't she the only daughter
那不是轩辕家
of Xuanyuan Jingcheng, the eldest grandson of the family?
嫡长孙轩辕敬城独女吗
Are you afraid of her?
你怕她
Afraid?
怕
Of course I'm not.
怕是不怕的
Then why do you hide?
那你躲什么
Old Huang and I
跟老黄
had met her.
遇见过她
What did you do to her?
你把她怎么了
Wasn't Wen Hua with us at that time?
这不是当时还有个温华吗
He thought Xuanyuan Qingfeng was good-looking.
他就是看那轩辕青锋长得不错
So he complimented her a little.
夸了两句
What did he say?
怎么夸的
He said something
也就是什么
about her hips
臀部形状啊
being suitable for childbirth.
利于生养啊
Wen Hua said that.
温华说的
Xuanyuan Qingfeng was unreasonable.
然后这轩辕青锋她不讲道理
She raced after us.
她追着我们打
It was just a misunderstanding.
就这么点小误会
Swordsmen wandering in the martial world
江湖儿女吗
should be generous.
应该大气些
She was generous enough to not kill you.
人家没杀你就够大气的了
Grandpa Wei.
魏爷爷
Follow the cavalry at a distance.
远远跟着前面那队人马
Yes.
明白
What's that look?
你这什么表情
Didn't you try to avoid her?
不是躲吗
Why do you follow her?
跟着干吗
Her family is useful to us.
轩辕家有用啊
The Xuanyuan Family controls the waterways of the world.
轩辕家族掌控天下水脉
Mount Hui and Mount Longhu are separated by a river.
徽山跟龙虎山一江之隔
The family alone
仅凭一个世家
can stand up to the four Longhu Arch-Taoists as an equal.
可以和龙虎四天师分庭抗礼
What a high status!
多高的地位
So Xu Xiao wants you
所以徐骁
to marry her?
让你联姻
Absolutely not.
绝对不是
To be honest,
实不相瞒
we're supposed to
这一行轩辕家
visit the Xuanyuan Family on the trip.
本来就是要去拜访的
It was a surprise that
倒是遇着这轩辕青锋
we met Xuanyuan Qingfeng.
是个意外
She seems to head towards Mount Hui, too.
看这方向她也是去徽山
Her family controls all the waterways.
她们家掌控天下水脉
Why does she ride a horse instead of taking a boat?
她怎么不坐船改骑马了
Why don't you ask her?
要不你去问问
Xuanyuan Qingfeng?
轩辕青锋
It's said she and her father are at odds.
听说她和她爹誓不两立
If we follow her,
这一脉顺下去
we may find some useful things.
或许有好处
Forget it.
算了
Let's kill Xu Fengnian first.
还是先杀小舅子要紧
We're just passing by.
路过的
We mean no harm.
并无恶意
You're quite combative.
杀气还挺重
Nice armor.
好盔甲
Nice move.
好刀法
Don't you attack us again?
不打啦
If I may ask,
能麻烦问一句
why did you attack us?
为什么要动刀
Do we know you?
我们认识吗
I was just awake.
刚睡醒
I was grumpy.
脾气躁
What about now?
这会儿呢
I can't kill you.
杀不掉
I'd better sleep.
睡觉
May I
阁下
know your name?
贵姓
Taking the shortcut,
小路更近
we'll return early.
能早归徽山
Take the shortcut.
走小路
Make way.
让路
Go.
上
Yuan Tingshan?
袁庭山
(Yuan Tingshan, Retainer of the Xuanyuan Family) Miss Qingfeng, are you going to the mountain?
小姐这是要回山
What if I am?
回山又怎样
Don't go.
还是别回了
You're just a retainer of my family.
你只是我轩辕家门客
How dare you stop me?
敢拦我的路
I'm just following orders.
我也是听令行事
Whose orders?
听谁的令
Old Ancestor issued a transfer order from Snowfield Guniujiang,
老祖于牯牛降大雪坪亲传调令
commanding me to return.
要我回山
Who dares to disobey his order?
轩辕家谁敢违命
Who do you think?
你说呢
Did my father send you?
我爹让你来的
What if I must go back?
我若非要回去呢
You can't go back.
回不去的
They're all combative.
杀性都重
Whose team is this?
谁家有这班底
Who are you?
你们是谁
Our young master came to save you.
我家公子是来救姑娘的
Could you tell me who you are?
阁下是谁
She is talking to you.
人家问你话呢
Could I not show my face?
要不然我不露面
In that case, why did you save her?
那你费劲救人家干吗
Think about it.
你想啊
At that time, I just gave her a little compliment.
当年我也就是夸了她几句
Wen Hua did that.
温华也就是夸了她几句
She raced after us for a few blocks.
她就追着我们打了几条街
Today I saved her life.
这如今我救她一命
We can call it even.
也算是扯平了吧
I appreciate your help.
多谢阁下相救
Please let me say thank you to your face.
还请当面道谢
It's you!
是你
Stop there!
你给我站住
Old Huang.
老黄
Something's wrong!
风紧
Wen Hua.
温华
Leave immediately!
扯呼
Miss, let me explain.
姑娘你听我解释
Nice hips. Suitable for childbirth.
这好屁股好生养
Those are all compliments.
那都是夸人的好词儿啊
Stop looking at me!
看什么看
Not just hips.
不只是屁股
You have nice waist, too.
你看这腰也好
Willow, water snake,
杨柳水蛇
wasp,
黄蜂
it's as slender and soft as them.
这都能对得上
Good figure. Great shape.
好身材好曲线
I'll kill you, rascal!
我杀了你臭流氓
How are you, Miss Xuanyuan?
轩辕姑娘好呀
Wait.
等等
You're mistaken.
姑娘你记错了
How could I be alone?
当时怎么是我一个人呢
Old Huang was with me,
明明还有一个老黄
and Wen Hua.
还有一个温华
Wen Hua said all those words.
那些话都是温华说的
I gave him a thumbs up at most,
我最多就在边上竖了个大拇指
and echoed a little.
帮了个腔
He was the ringleader.
他才是罪魁祸首
You...
你
Miss,
姑娘姑娘
I made friends carelessly.
我也是交友不慎
We were both victims.
咱们都是受害者
How dare you show up again?
你还敢出现
We have a bond, right?
这不有缘吗
See you next time.
后会有期
Shu Xiu.
舒羞
Grandpa Wei.
魏爷爷
Rest assured.
放心
He can't escape.
他逃不掉的
Who are you exactly?
你到底是谁
It was so close.
就差那么一点儿
You have no compassion for womanhood.
都不知道怜香惜玉
I care about you in vain.
姐姐白疼你了
Why don't you
那要不
let me care about you?
我来心疼心疼姐姐
That's sweet.
小嘴真甜
Did he run again?
又跑了
Dare he take liberties with me?
调戏到老娘头上了
He's right ahead.
就在前面
Go.
追
Are you Xu Fengnian from North Liang?
你是北椋徐凤年
Everyone hates Xu Fengnian.
我这个身份人人喊打
Why do I want to pretend to be him?
用不着假扮吧
Who was the man that stopped you?
刚才要拦着你那个人是谁呀
None of your business.
与你何干
It seems that someone doesn't want you to go back.
看来是有人不想让姑娘回徽山
Shall we travel together?
不如同行
It's a dangerous journey.
这一路可不好走
Are you Xu Xiao's son?
你徐骁儿子啊
Have you
姑娘是
just figured it out?
才理清楚这关系
So, you do
这么看来
look like him.
是有些像
What did you say?
姑娘你说什么
Are you going to Mount Hui, too?
你也上徽山
I'm going to Mount Longhu.
我去龙虎
On the opposite side of the river.
一江之隔
All right.
刚好
Let's go part of the way together.
同行一段
Where is he?
哪儿去了
Did he cross the river?
过河了
Be careful!
小心
Thanks, Senior.
多谢前辈
Is it some swordplay or hidden weapon?
这是剑法还是暗器
Handle of the Big Dipper, Peach Wood Sword Array.
三十六天罡桃木剑阵
Why did you use a jade sword, then?
桃木剑阵为什么用玉剑
Because it looks noble.
这不显得贵气吗
Take the assassin to His Highness.
把人给世子带去
Yes.
好
No way.
不可能啊
I gave him a push with all my strength.
我这全力一掌
Even if he didn't die,
就算不死
he couldn't escape without a sound.
也不可能这么悄无声息地逃走
Drop the act.
别装了
You are conscious.
你又没晕
If I want to kill you,
我真要杀你
I wouldn't have saved you.
刚才就不会救你
Why did you save me?
干吗救我
The one you gave a sneak attack
你动刀偷袭的
is Xu Fengnian of North Liang.
是北椋徐凤年
If there is a chance,
有机会
shall we do it again together?
联手再杀一次啊
What if I don't join hands with you?
我要是不跟你联手呢
I don't feel like forcing others.
我不勉强别人
But think it clearly.
不过你想清楚
You attacked him.
你对他动了刀子
Do you think North Liang will let you go?
北椋会放过你吗
Will the Xuanyuan Family make an enemy of Xu Xiao
轩辕家会为了一个门客
just for a retainer?
与徐骁为敌吗
When do you take action?
你什么时候动手
Let's talk about it next time.
下次见面再聊
I hope you can live until then.
希望你能活到那时候
Won't you wait for your men?
你不等你的那些手下了
They'll catch up.
他们赶得上来
You're in such a hurry going back to Mount Hui.
姑娘这么着急回徽山
Do you have anything important?
是有要事在身
Sort of.
算是
Who was the man that stopped you?
拦你那人是谁
Yuan Tingshan.
袁庭山
One of our retainers.
我家门客
Dare a retainer stop his master?
门客拦主人
He probably followed my father's order.
应该是我爹让他拦的
What else do you want to know?
你还想知道什么
Will it be inconvenient for you
轩辕家的大事
to tell me about the important matters of your family?
会不会不方便让我知道
Yes.
会
Just ignore me.
当我没问
Do you try to meddle with our affairs?
北椋的手想伸进徽山
Have some water?
喝水不
No.
不用
Last time I was so angry with you
上一次见光顾着生气了
that I didn't see your face clearly.
没仔细看你的面容
There is nothing to see.
有什么可看的
Your face will
你这面容
please my mother.
我娘应该喜欢
I...
我我我
I'll take a break.
我歇会儿啊
Don't you think she is crazy?
你说她是不是心智有问题
Xu Fengnian,
徐凤年
tell me the truth.
说真的
Have you
你是不是
met her mother?
还见过她娘
Definitely not.
真没有
Let's get to the point.
咱们说正事
Senior.
前辈
Do you know the Old Ancestor of the Xuanyuan Family?
你知不知道轩辕家那位老祖
Once at Snowfield Guniujiang of Mount Hui,
徽山牯牛降大雪坪上
Xuanyuan Dapan
轩辕大磐
had a fight with me.
和我斗过剑呢
Is he still alive?
还活着啊他
Who won?
谁赢了
I only lost to Wang Xianzhi.
我只输过王仙芝啊
What realm did you say Xuanyuan Dapan had achieved?
你刚说那轩辕大磐什么境界
Celestial Realm.
天象境
How could he be the same as me?
怎么跟我一样啊
Does it mean he is good?
那不是很强
It doesn't mean anything.
境界有什么用
What matters is fighting capacity.
能打才行
Kid,
小子啊
do you have designs on Mount Hui?
你想动徽山哪
The Xuanyuan Family controls the world's waterways.
轩辕家掌控天下水路
It's very useful.
用处大得很
How do you subdue it?
怎么收服
Why don't you
要不
marry the girl outside?
娶了外头那丫头
I will never sell myself.
我徐凤年绝不卖身
What's going on
她和她爹
with her and her father?
怎么回事
They're said to have a very bad relationship.
据说轩辕青锋和她爹关系极差
So she's away from home all year round.
所以常年不回徽山
Why is their relationship so bad?
她和她爹为什么关系差
Her father is the eldest grandson of their family.
她爹轩辕敬城是轩辕家嫡长孙
By rights,
按理来说
he should be in charge of the family business.
应该由他执掌家业
But all members of the family
可是现在整个徽山上下
don't take him seriously.
没人把他放在眼里
Why?
为什么
He likes reading
他只爱看书
rather than practicing martial arts.
不曾习武
What's wrong with reading?
爱看书有什么不好啊
After all, he is in a martial arts family.
轩辕一族毕竟是江湖世家
He can't run family business, indeed.
那是掌不了家业
Except for not practicing martial arts,
不仅不习武
he is said to be weak
据传他性子软弱
and can't do anything great.
不成大器
He is a loser.
是个废物
Isn't he the same as you?
那不是跟你一样
What do you mean?
什么叫跟我一样
You had a reputation
你之前的名声
as bad as him, didn't you?
不就是跟他一样吗
I...
我
You're right.
也是啊
I might have a worse reputation than he does.
我之前的名声没准比他还差
You're grim
你小子心狠
and hard to guess.
藏得深
Maybe it's the same
轩辕家族那小子
with that guy.
搞不好也是如此
If so,
若真如此的话
he's even harder to guess.
他藏得可比我久
The key points are,
其实关键就一点
why does Xuanyuan Qingfeng return to Mount Hui
轩辕青锋为什么回徽山
and why does her father stop her?
她爹为什么拦她
We can see through the whole game if we figure it out.
明白这个整盘棋都看透了
I think ever since you met Cao Changqing,
我发现你自从见了曹长卿之后
you've become much smarter.
聪明了不少
Sharp.
厉害厉害
You're a real queen.
女王风范
No.
不是
I'm always smart.
我本来就很聪明啊
You've been reading every day.
大哥天天读书
What have you read about?
读出什么来了
The spirit of people,
读春秋大义
the mediocre life,
读众生碌碌
the rights and wrongs,
读是非曲直
and
读
the formless universal way.
大道无形
That's much.
读这么多
Does it do any good to you?
有什么用
Sure.
有用
I won't be distracted.
心不会乱
I heard one thing just now.
我刚刚听说一件事情啊
The retainer who uses a blade,
那个耍刀的门客
what's his name?
叫什么来着
Yuan Tingshan.
袁庭山
Yes.
对
I heard he went down the mountain.
我听说他下山了
Before he went,
在下山前
he seemed to have seen you.
好像还见过大哥
Yes, he did.
有这回事
Why?
怎么
Do you want to stop Qingfeng from coming back?
想拦青锋回家
Jingcheng,
大哥
Old Ancestor picked your daughter as his successor
老祖宗选了你家女儿
to inherit our family martial arts
入大雪坪问鼎阁
at Wending Pavilion of Snowfield.
接受武学的传承
What good fortune she has.
这是何等的造化
You sent someone to stop her.
你派人去拦
Are you out of your mind?
读书读糊涂了大哥
As her father,
做父亲的
I have to do something for her.
总得做些什么吧
There are many ways back home.
回山的路这么多
How could Yuan Tingshan alone
一个袁庭山
stop her?
怎么拦人
Will he just happen to run into her?
就这么巧就能碰上
Enough of jokes.
笑话也听够了
I won't disturb you any longer.
我就不陪大哥了
I'm going to visit my sister-in-law.
我还得去问候嫂子
By the way, she raises good fish.
对了
Have you seen it yet?
你去看了没有
I'm sorry.
对不住
I forgot that,
我给忘了
of all the people on the mountain,
整座徽山
only you are not allowed to
人人都能进嫂子的住处
step into your wife's residence.
唯独大哥你不能进
Reading is useful.
读书有用
It keeps you from being distracted.
心不会乱
So go on reading.
那你慢慢读
Can't your young master eat on his own?
你家世子连饭都不会吃吗
They're back.
他们回来了
Your Highness, we didn't catch him.
世子 没抓住
The guy
这家伙
is crafty.
滑溜得很
It doesn't matter.
没抓住不要紧
Down the river is Mount Hui.
沿江而下就是徽山
He doesn't have any chance to stop her.
他也没机会拦人了
What do you say?
你说呢
I'll have a walk.
我闲逛一会儿
Enjoy yourself.
请便
Kid.
小子
Aren't you bored?
不闷吗
Come out for a walk.
出来走走
Are you insane?
你傻了吗
Outwardly,
明面上
I was taken away by Uncle Chess Master.
我被棋诏叔叔给带走了
What do you want?
干吗呀
It's kind of fun
一个人待着
to be here alone.
倒是有点儿意思
But how do you relieve yourself?
就是这如厕怎么办呢
None of your business.
要你管啊
Stop messing around.
你们两个别闹了
Listen to me first.
等我把话说完了再闹
Yes.
您说
Xuanyuan Qingfeng isn't wandering.
轩辕青锋不是去闲逛
There is someone skulking in the direction she's going to.
她去的那个方向藏了个人
How do you know?
这您都知道
It's hard to fool me from such a distance.
这距离瞒过我的没几个
It's nothing that she wants to meet someone secretly.
偷偷见个人也没什么
After all, I have a bad reputation.
毕竟我这北椋世子名声不好
The man she's about to see is interesting.
见的人倒是有点意思
Do you know who she sees?
您还知道她见的是谁
Are you hurt?
受伤了
I was attacked by three people
三人围攻
and got a blow.
被打了一掌
How badly it is?
伤重吗
I may die.
搞不好会死的
Really?
这么严重
It won't stop me from going back, though.
还能坚持回山
What order did my father give you?
我爹给你什么命令
Don't hurt you.
不能伤你
Don't let you go back.
不能让你回山
Then why Old Ancestor let me go back?
那老祖为什么召我回山啊
You were chosen to enter Wending Pavilion
让你入问鼎阁
and be taught by Old Ancestor himself.
受老祖亲传
It's terrific.
天大好事啊
My uncle didn't stop me.
我那叔叔都没拦我
Why doesn't my father want me to attain the highest level in one step?
反而自家亲爹怕我一步登天
Your father was prepared.
你爹早有准备
Those around you were all his informers.
你身边人全是他眼线
I know.
我知道
Taking the shortcut, we'll return early.
小路更近能早归徽山
Take the shortcut.
走小路
I took them out at one time.
一次铲除干净
It was lucky.
还挺顺利
What was annoying was a lord's heir coming out of nowhere.
莫名其妙冒出个世子
Why did you attack Xu Fengnian?
你对徐凤年动刀做什么
I couldn't help it.
忍不住
What do you mean?
什么叫忍不住
I can't help but want to see
忍不住想看看
what the superior lord's heir
这种高高在上的世子
looks like when he dies.
死的时候会是什么样
Yuan Tingshan,
袁庭山
don't go crazy.
别真变成疯子
Does my father have any reason
我爹不让我回山
to stop me from going back?
总要有个理由吧
He didn't say.
他没说
Forget it.
算了
The general situation has settled.
反正大局已定
Go back to recuperate.
回山后你安心养伤
I'll give you a chance in the future
今后自会给你机会
to learn our unique martial arts.
习得问鼎阁内绝学
Good.
好啊
Take a shortcut.
抄小道回去吧
Don't let anyone see you.
别让人瞧见
Go.
去吧
I'll wait for you at Mount Hui.
我在徽山等你
What are you doing?
逛什么呢
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
It's time to go.
该上路了
OK.
好
There comes the news that
山下传来消息
my niece comes to the river.
我那侄女已经在江边了
You've been apart for a long time.
久别重逢
You should go with me to pick her up.
大哥应该跟我一起去山下接人
Someone.
来人
Help him to go down the mountain.
扶人下山
Don't bother.
不用
I can walk by myself.
我自己走
Please.
请吧
How long has it been since you came down last time?
大哥有多久没下山了
Can you stand well?
站得稳吗
Do you need someone to hold you?
要不要找人扶你
Are there people from Mount Longhu?
这儿还有龙虎山的人
Fishermen.
打渔的
It's near Mount Longhu.
这儿离这龙虎山近
Everyone wears a Taoist robe.
个个都披个道袍
They have the strength of character.
好根骨的
What?
根骨
They look like fools.
像个傻子
The Xuanyuan Family has stood for a hundred years
轩辕家百年屹立不摇
by courtesy and righteousness.
靠的是礼与义
Courtesy?
礼
Righteousness?
义
Don't we need honor and shame?
那要不要廉耻呢
Jingcheng,
大哥
do you read to get stupid?
你真的是读书读傻了
Our family has won dignity
轩辕世家风光至今
by hard fist
靠的是拳头够硬
and strong muscle.
实力够强
Look,
你看
they're coming.
人到了
Is that your boat?
你家的船
Qingfeng, you finally come back.
青锋归山
I come down
做叔叔的
to pick you up with your father.
陪着你爹亲自来接你
It's been years.
这么多年了
It's time to come back.
也该回来啦
Old Ancestor wants to take Qingfeng as his disciple.
老祖宗要收青锋
Who can stop him?
谁也拦不住
Is the one with the biggest voice
声音最大的那个
your third uncle, Xuanyuan Jingxuan?
就是你三叔轩辕敬宣吧
I heard that over the years,
听说这么多年
he has been in charge of your family business.
轩辕家一直由他执掌家业
If nothing else,
别的不说
he's got quite a good voice.
嗓门不错
Thank you, Mr. Xu.
多谢徐世子
See you.
告辞
Already?
这就走了
Mr. Xu,
徐世子
we won't tread in muddy water
徽山不会跳进浑水
or attach ourselves to North Liang.
也不会依附北椋
Let's say goodbye.
就此道别
Huangman'er.
黄蛮儿
What is he looking at?
他看什么呢
Jingcheng,
大哥
the guy who sent your daughter back,
送你女儿回来的这小子是谁
do you know him?
你知道吗
I've never seen him.
未曾见过
It must be another swordsman
想必又是
who tries to play up to us.
借机讨好徽山的江湖子弟
Qingfeng.
青锋
Huangman'er.
黄蛮儿
Fengnian.
哥
They're brothers.
这是对兄弟啊
What a coincidence.
这么巧
He is really Young Master Longxiang.
还真是小王爷
Isn't he afraid of water?
他不是怕水吗
Fengnian!
哥
Senior,
前辈
give me a ride.
送我一程
I didn't expect my Snakes in Sleeves
没想到老夫的两袖青蛇
would become his mount.
竟然成了坐骑了
Charge him.
收钱啊
He must pay for renting cattle and horses.
租牛租马都要收钱
Don't let him take advantage of you.
你可别便宜他
Little girl.
小丫头
Fengnian.
哥
Aren't you afraid of water?
不是怕水吗
Not anymore.
已经不怕了
On the mountain,
山上啊
some hawthorns are already ripe.
有些山楂已经熟了
Since then,
自打那天起呀
the kid has been waiting for you by the river.
这孩子就天天在江边等你
After some time,
等着等着
he isn't afraid of water any more.
他就不怕水了
Awesome.
了不起
Fengnian,
哥
fish.
有鱼
A guest must do as his host does.
咱们入乡随俗
Let's have some vegetarian food.
吃点斋饭就行了
Don't embarrass your master.
别让你师父为难
Don't worry.
没事
It won't embarrass him.
老道士师父不为难
He cooks fish soup.
他会做鱼汤
Fengnian, let's have fish.
哥吃鱼
We can't have vegetarian food every day.
这天天吃斋菜也不是个事啊
Don't mention fish to other people.
上龙虎 可别提鱼的事啊
Don't worry.
放心
Nobody will mention it.
没人提鱼
Put the fish down.
把鱼放下吧
Zhao Xituan?
赵希抟
One of the four Longhu Arch-Taoists?
龙虎四天师
I heard Zhao Xituan
我听说赵希抟
took Xu Xiao's son as a disciple.
收了徐骁的儿子当徒弟
Xu Fengnian.
徐凤年
should we wait for them?
用不用等他们呀
Don't bother.
咱们先走
They'll catch up with us.
他们会跟上
OK.
好嘞
How did your daughter
你的女儿
know the son of Lord of North Liang?
怎么会认识北椋世子
I have no idea.
我也不知
Let's go.
走了
Go back.
回山
You've been away from home for years.
青锋离家数年
Now you come back.
今日归山
I feel relieved.
我也是放心了
Was the one with you
与你同行的
Xu Fengnian of North Liang?
是北椋徐凤年
Yes.
是
Is he an old acquaintance of yours?
与他是旧识
We've met once.
之前见过一面
I don't know much about him.
不算熟悉
Really?
是吗
Then why did he send you back?
不熟还送你回山啊
We just went the same way.
或许是顺路吧
(Mount Hui) Same way?
顺路
Qingfeng,
青锋
our family has been lasted
咱们轩辕家
for hundreds of years.
传承数百年
We can't let others
可不能把命脉
control our lifeline.
交到别人手上
Bright ideas.
三叔高见
Uncle.
二叔
(Xuanyuan Jingyi) Qingfeng.
青锋啊
(Second Son of the Xuanyuan Family) You surely have the honor.
你还真有面子
Your second uncle usually doesn't show up.
你二叔平常可是不露面的
Tomorrow, Old Ancestor will call you into Wending Pavilion.
明日老祖召你入问鼎阁
Uncle,
回二叔
I already knew.
我已经知道了
You should go tomorrow.
明日便去
Yes.
是
(Mount Hui) Your second uncle devotes himself to martial arts.
你二叔全心习武
On the mountain,
在这徽山上
except for Old Ancestor,
除了老祖宗
he takes no notice of anybody.
就没人在他眼里
Qingfeng,
青锋
you'll be Old Ancestor's direct disciple.
将来你可是老祖宗的亲传
Our family
轩辕家
may be handed over to you.
说不定就要交到你的手上了
Uncle,
三叔
you're the real pillar of our family.
才是轩辕家的擎天玉柱
You haven't seen each other for years.
你们父女多年没见
Have a good talk.
好好聊聊
I'm going to see my mother.
我去看娘
Qingfeng.
青锋
What can I do for you?
什么事
What's your relationship with Xu Fengnian?
那徐凤年对你是什么意思
That's all you want to ask?
你就问这个
If you turn to him,
你若投靠
are you sure he will support you?
可有把握让徐凤年支持你
Maneuver among various groupings.
合纵连横
Did you read about it from some book?
书里读来的
You want to trade me for the support of North Liang,
想用我换北椋支持
so that you can get the chance
让你有机会
to take back the power of ruling the family?
夺回嫡子长孙的世家之权
Mount Longhu Sect is number one in the world.
这龙虎山是天下第一门派
Why are you so poor?
怎么这么穷啊
Arch-Taoists' Office is on the mountain.
天师府在山上
Worshipers all go over there.
拜山的去那边
We don't have the good fortune.
我这逍遥观可就没这福气喽
Why don't you live on the mountain?
你不住龙虎山上
It's tiring to live with so many people.
人太多 活着累
Besides, the kid
再说这孩子
isn't suitable to live
也不适合住在那
at a disturbing place.
人心浮沉之地啊
Fengzi Battalion is stationed outside the temple.
凤字营驻扎观外
We are at your disposal.
随时听候调遣
Born to be Diamond Realm.
天生金刚境啊
He's the only one in the world.
人间仅见
Your little brother
你这个弟弟
will be invincible by achieving Void Realm.
入指玄境就能举世无敌
Don't try to achieve Celestial Realm.
可别入天象境
It requires unity of heaven and man.
天象境要天人归一的
I don't think he can endure it.
这身骨怕有劫数
My disciple is practicing
我这弟子啊
Big Dream of Spring and Autumn.
修的是大梦春秋
He can survive the calamity of heaven and earth by the heart arts.
可以借心法渡天地劫
You care about your disciple very much.
你这个做师父的倒是用心
The direct disciple is more important than my own life.
嫡传弟子比命还重要啊
God of Sword.
李剑神
Long time no see.
好久未见
Do you still remember me?
您还记得我吗
Not really.
不太记得
It's me.
我啊
Zhao Xituan of Mount Longhu.
龙虎的赵希抟哪
Is the fish ready?
鱼好了吗
Almost.
快了快了快了
Please be patient for a while.
您再耐心等等
How could he not remember me?
怎么连我都不记得了
Don't wink at him again.
不用使眼色了
Jiang Ni came in through the backyard.
姜泥从后院进来的
How could I not know there was one more person in the carriage?
车上多个人我还能不知道啊
Who else knows?
还有谁知道
Don't tell anyone.
别说出去
Of course.
那是自然
Jiang Ni?
姜泥
How are you?
小王爷好
Wait for me.
等我回来
What's going on?
什么情况